Jongwon Lee

Fremont, CA | (510)-766-6853 | jongwonlee12345@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://jongwonlee123.github.io/react-portfolio/

GitHub Link: https://github.com/JongwonLee123

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jongwon-lee-39a3ba203/

SUMMARY

Solutions-driven front-end web developer applying strong technical skillset towards building functional server-side applications. Have experience in front-end and back-end web development through UC Berkeley's extension boot camp and worked on projects to utilize technologies such as React and MongoDB. Current College Freshman with two years of experience in C++. Collaborative and eager to learn more about programming.

PROJECTS

Bazaar buddies

A website that allows users to view products and post their own to others Repository Link: https://github.com/skytexier/Bazaar-Buddies

January 2023

- Created the Apollo server and got the connection with the MongoDB database to work and collect inputted and collected data from user
- Helped debug issues with the database collecting information
- Created the routes and models for the users and products

Dinner-spinner

A website that shares recipes with other users

November 2022

Repository Link: https://github.com/c1flores/Dinner-Spinner

- Utilized the multer npm package to collect images from the user for the recipes
- Helped with creating the MySQL connection and seeds
- Worked on creating the handlebars for the pages used in the website

Marvel API September 2022

A website that shows users marvel comics and youtube videos utilizing APIs

Repository link: https://github.com/Alwayswithaname/project11/tree/feature/helper

Deployed link: https://alwayswithaname.github.io/project11/

- Utilized the marvel API and collected comics to display depending on what superhero the user wanted
- Created the page for the comics and styled it using CSS and HTML
- Helped debug issues with the main page and youtube API

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C++, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Insomnia, Visual Studio Code

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

English Tutor | Online:

July 2022 - December 2022

Composed reading materials, guided process, and drafted creative ways to talk with the student. Developed a reading system to create a better understanding of the learning material. Difficult to communicate, but able to teach by learning and studying material ahead of time

- Improved teaching skills
- Developed better communication skills
- Recognized for dedication and effort

Chipotle Mexican Grill Line Worker | Fremont, CA:

January 2022-July 2022

Operated customer service, cooperated in food preparation, and established a secure workplace. Fashioned more efficient food service to combat queues.

- Recognized for reliability
- Devised problem-solving skills in difficult situations
- Mentored new employees
- Established positive connections

VOLUNTEER AND LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Ohlone Engineering Society

January 2023 - Present

Ohlone College - Fremont, CA

Inter-Club Council Representative

- Attended weekly meetings in the council
- Determined important decisions for the club
- Informed club of significant events
- Observed and collaborated in club meetings

Tule Ponds at Tyson Lagoon

September 2018 – January 2019

Tule Ponds - Fremont, CA

Restoration of native plants and animals at Tyson Lagoon

- Removed invasive weeds by learning and pulling out weeds
- Planted milkweed by moving them to the desired location, removing the soil, and watering them

EDUCATION

Ohlone College - Fremont, CA August 2022 - Present

Computer Science

Transfer to the University of California (upcoming)

May 2024

UC Berkeley Extension Web Development - virtual January 2023

Certificate

Mission San Jose Highschool - Fremont, CA August 2018-June 2022

Highschool Diploma